What kind of food do you eat?
你平时吃什么食物？
Are you conscious of the types of food you consume or do you stuff yourself silly with whatever is available?
你会留意自己摄入的食物种类，还是有什么就吃什么，吃到撑为止？
Today, we are constantly bombarded with media reports about research on the right diet to follow to help us maintain a healthy lifestyle or lose weight - but it's hard to know which one to pick and, once chosen, it's harder still to stick to it.
如今，我们不断被关于健康饮食研究的媒体报道轰炸，声称遵循相应饮食方式能帮我们维持健康生活状态或减肥——但我们很难确定该选哪一种，而且就算选好了，要坚持下去就更难了。
And now there's another choice to get our teeth into.
现在，又有一种新的饮食选择可供我们尝试。
A flexitarian diet involves eating plant-based foods and only occasionally eating meat and fish.
弹性素食饮食法以植物性食物为主，偶尔食用肉类和鱼类。
You might think this is a halfway house to being a vegetarian by not completely abstaining from meat.
你可能会觉得，这种饮食方式没有完全戒肉，算是成为素食者的过渡状态。
But if vegetarianism is hard to swallow and you fancy chomping on the occasional lean steak, then this could be the choice for you.
但如果你无法接受素食主义，却又喜欢偶尔啃一块瘦牛排，那么弹性素食或许就是适合你的选择。
This eating style allows you to supplement some ingredients that you wouldn't get in a stricter vegan diet – another trend growing in popularity.
这种饮食方式能帮你补充一些严格素食饮食中摄取不到的营养成分，严格素食也是当下越来越受欢迎的一种饮食趋势。
And like veganism, flexitarianism isn't about eating carefully to help you lose a few pounds - it's something people choose for ethical reasons, to help the planet.
和素食主义一样，弹性素食的目的并非是通过精心控制饮食来减重——人们选择这种饮食方式是出于伦理考量，是为了保护地球。
And a study into the global food system and how it affects the climate, has found that eating mainly plant-based foods is one of three key steps towards a sustainable future for all by 2050.
一项针对全球食物系统及其对气候影响的研究发现，以植物性食物为主的饮食模式，是到2050年实现全人类可持续发展未来的三大关键举措之一。
This research found that food waste will need to be halved and farming practices will also have to improve to achieve this.
该研究发现，要实现这一目标，食物浪费量需要减半，农业耕作方式也必须改进。
But without a single solution, a combined approach is needed.
但目前没有能单独解决问题的方案，需要采取综合性的措施。
Dr Marco Springmann from the University of Oxford was one of the lead authors of the report. He told the BBC "We really found that a combination of measures would be needed to stay within environmental limits and those include changes towards healthier more plant-based diets."
牛津大学的马尔科·施普林曼博士是这份报告的主要作者之一，他在接受BBC采访时表示：“事实上我们发现，要想将对环境的影响控制在合理范围内，需要采取一系列综合措施，其中就包括向更健康、更偏向植物性的饮食模式转变。”
But whereas vegans think it's wrong for animals to be killed for food, flexitarians believe eating meat once in a while is acceptable.
但是，虽然素食主义者认为为了吃肉而宰杀动物是不对的，弹性素食者却觉得偶尔吃点肉是可以接受的。
And Dr Springmann agrees - as long as we "treat it as a luxury, it’s probably OK but you shouldn’t have more than one serving of red meat, which includes beef and pork, per week."
施普林曼博士也认同这一观点——只要我们“把肉类当作一种奢侈品，适量食用或许没问题，但每周食用红肉（包括牛肉和猪肉）的份量不应超过一份。”
And here's another fact to digest: If we moved to this type of diet, the study found that greenhouse gas emissions from agriculture would be cut by more than half.
还有一个值得深思的事实：研究发现，如果我们都采用这种饮食方式，农业产生的温室气体排放量将减少一半以上。